

ARCHANA ARORA H-95 West Patel Nagar, New Delhi-110008

Email: - archana.arora1977@gmail.com

MOBILE: 9910040699

Career Summary

Seeking a challenging position as an *Front office Desk / Administration / Office Coordinator / office Assistant* to apply my 20 years' experience and skills as a office administrator to ensure effective functioning of office work. using a positive attitude, great attention to detail and accuracy, and a desire to succeed in a fast-paced environment to make a difference in the office administrative procedures.

Technical Skills

- Computer's (MS World, Excel, PowerPoint & Outlook)
- **❖** Fax
- Photo copier/Scanner
- Internet
- Digital Marketing Course- World Press

Key Responsibilities Handled

Communication of messages, receiving phone calls, transferring calls, using judgment calls regarding nature of business and urgency of situation.-Data entry duties depending on the task set. Assisting the office maintenance team in organization and repair of office equipment

Work Experience

- 1. Working as an *Office Assistant cum Admin*, for *M/s. RIC Projects Pvt. Ltd.* at Naraina Vihar, New Delhi from Nov 2016 to March 2019.
- Complete Office Administration / Office Assistant
- ❖ Answer all incoming calls and handle callers inquiries whenever possible
- ❖ Coordinate and follow-up with the customers.
- Processing PO and arranging material.
- Maintain Analysis & D.O Items.
- ❖ Working on Word, Excel, Power Point, Email etc
- ❖ Maintain the general filing system, file all correspondence and database maintenance.
- ❖ Assist in the planning and preparation of meetings, conferences etc
- ❖ Maintain office supplies (stationary, Pantry material etc)
- ❖ Coordinate the repair and maintenance of office equipment
- Perform other related duties as required
- ❖ Coordinate the activities of office support staff.
- ❖ Managing multiple travel agencies for booking of air/railway tickets
- ❖ Handle petty cash, floats and expenses
- ❖ Good typing and note taking skills i.e. a minimum of 40 words per minute

- 2. Worked as an *Front Office cum Administration* for *M/s Adhunik Metaliks Ltd.* at Connaught Place, New Delhi from June 2006 to October-2016.
- Welcome guests and decide whether they should be given right of entry to meet specific individuals
- Oversee office's filing and record management needs
- ❖ Managing multiple travel agencies for booking of air/railway tickets
- ❖ Arrange for executives' travel and accommodation logistics
- ❖ Maintenance of Office Cars/Booking of vehicles.
- Schedule meetings and prepare appropriate agendas for meetings and conferences
- ❖ Schedule and assign administrative projects and ensure that results are expedited
- ❖ Prepare administrative reports for the benefit of the management
- ❖ Handle administrative issues and conflicts in accordance to the company's policies
- Prepare memos, invoices, reports, and financial statements by means of word processing, spreadsheet, database, and presentation software such as PowerPoint
- Verifying their respective bills and forward to Accounts for payment
- Handle petty cash, floats and expenses.
- ❖ House Keeping, Stationery and Office Hygiene Management
- ❖ Assisted the employees in building and maintaining their individual databases.
- ❖ Should be expert in Ms Office, Excel, Power Point and Internet
- ❖ Communicate clearly with work colleagues using emails etc.
- ❖ Collect, count, and disburse money, do basic bookkeeping and complete banking transactions.
- Checking attendance of employees & other facility staff daily and updating same in Excel.
- Communicate with customers, employees, and other individuals to answer questions, disseminate or explain information, take orders and address complaints.
- ❖ Handle telephone calls and relay messages
- Compile, copy, sort, and file records of office activities, business transactions, and other activities.
- ❖ Complete and mail bills, contracts, policies, invoices, or checks.
- Operate office machines, such as photocopiers and scanners, facsimile machines, voice mail systems and personal computers.
- ❖ Compute, record, and proofread data and other information, such as records or reports.
- Good typing and note taking skills i.e. a minimum of 50 words per minute.
- * Review files, records, and other documents to obtain information to respond to requests.
- ❖ Work within a busy office environment, and support office teams in order to ensure the smooth running of day-to-day activities.
- 3. Worked as an *Office Assistant* for *M/s. Chander Parkash & Co. (CA Firm)* at Rajendra Place, New Delhi from May. 2005 to May 2006.
- ❖ Welcome guests and decide whether they should be given right of entry to meet specific individuals
- Oversee office's filing and record management needs
- ❖ Schedule meetings and prepare appropriate agendas for meetings and conferences
- ❖ Should be expert in Ms Office, Excel, Power Point and Internet
- ❖ Communicate clearly with work colleagues using emails etc.
- * Compile, copy, sort, and file records of office activities, business transactions, and other activities.
- ❖ Complete and mail bills, contracts, policies, invoices, or checks.
- . Compute, record, and proofread data and other information, such as records or reports.
- Good typing and note taking skills i.e. a minimum of 50 words per minute.
- * Review files, records, and other documents to obtain information to respond to requests.
- Work within a busy office environment, and support office teams in order to ensure the smooth running of day-to-day activities.

4. Worked as an *Front office Executive* for *M/s. Monaa International (Export House)* at Nariana, Industrial Area, New Delhi from As a from May. 1998 to May 2005.

Perform duties too varied and diverse to be classified in any specific office clerical occupation, requiring limited knowledge of office management systems and procedures. Clerical duties may be assigned in accordance with the office procedures of individual establishments and may include a combination of answering telephones, bookkeeping, typing or word processing, office machine operation, and filing. Sample of reported job titles: Administrative Assistant, Office Manager, Receptionist, Clerk, Secretary, Office Assistant, Office Clerk, Customer Service Representative, Office Coordinator.

Education

- 10th Pass, 1994 from SD Girls Sr. Sec. School for CBSE Board in Delhi
- 12th Pass, 1996 from SD Girls Sr. Sec. School for CBSE Board in Delhi (Vocational course include office Management, Typing & Stenography)
- B.A (Prog.), with Arts from Delhi University since 1999

Personal Details

Husband's Name : Mr. Gopi Arora

Date of Birth : 23rd August, 1977

Marital Status : Married

Language Known : English, Hindi